Hello everyone, today I am talking about the
new plan of ICICI Prudential,
ICICI Prudential Signature Assure
Plan.
I have been in the insurance industry for 20 years.
I
feel that this plan is the best plan I have ever seen. It means that wealth creation will happen while we are
alive. If
we are not, it will be family
protection. That is, the
company will take the remaining premiums and the
waiver of premium. Signature Assure Plan is
a plan that has added many features.
Signature
Plan was the best plan.
That is, Signature Assure Plan is a plan that has added three more features. To
know the details about this plan, watch the video till the end. If this is
your first time watching this channel, let me
introduce myself. My name is Binoy. I have been
working in the field of insurance investment and banking for the last 20 years.
[Music]
First of all, what is Signature? ICI
Signature Plan and ICI Signature?  Let's see the
difference between the ICI Signature Plan and the Assure Plan. The ICI Signature Plan
is a pure wealth creation plan in which the customer
pays for seven or 10 years. The Uli Plan is a
plan that helps in wealth creation in a good way according to market growth. The charge is
low. From the tenth year onwards, there are wealth
boosters, that is, if any
charge has been taken, it will be returned
like a road. If
any charge has been
taken, it will be returned. The
Signature Plan is the best plan among the Uli plans. It is
for wealth creation and this is where the Signature
Assure Plan
company has added
child education,
child marriage, family support, which are important for us along with wealth creation.
What will happen if we do not have wealth creation? If
we do, as mentioned above,  The
benefit in the signature plan
comes, that is, if we have an
unfortunate death, the
plan closes, the
amount is returned, the sum assured is
returned, the sum assured or the fund
value, whichever is greater, is returned to the
nominee, and the plan
ends. That is how the signature plan
Signature Assure plan has three other
benefits added,
that is, if death occurs, the unfortunate event occurs to the
policy holder, if life is assured, the lump sum amount, i.e., for example, for two
lakhs, is
given 10 times 20 lakhs, and the
plan continues after that. The rest of the
premiums are paid by the company, i.e., it is a
plan that is paid for two to seven years. If not taken,
the company will pay the remaining five years of premium, i.e., there is an
option called Waiver of Premium. There is an income benefit,
i.e., 10% of the sum assured every
year that comes closer, i.e., if the term is 20 years.  For the
next 18 or 17 or 18
years, 10% of the sum assured, i.e.
10% of 20 lakhs, is paid every year with a deposit of Rs 2 lakh. The
amount at maturity is also paid,
i.e. the sum assured is paid first, the death
sum assured or fund value is
paid, the income is paid 10% of the sum assured, and the
remaining fund value is
paid. So
I
feel it is a complete plan. I can say that
I have not seen a plan with so many benefits. The
Signature Assure Plan is the best plan. Let's see how the Signature Assure
Plan works.
This is the customer
service term, i.e. nothing
unfortunate happens to the customer. 20 years. This is the
premium payment term for seven
years. The policy term is 20 years.
That is what this plan is looking at. For 20
years, nothing
happens to the customer.  An example is a 35
year old person. If nothing happens to the person till the age of 55, then if there is no death,
the person
pays the premium for seven years.
Let's say the example is around 2 lakhs and
pays the premium. After that, in the
tenth year, what is the fund value? The average fund
value of the total fund value is
25% of the fund value. 25% is added to this plan. Similarly, in the 15th year, the average fund value is 25% of the fund value. In the
20th year, what is the total fund value? It is
added to its average fund value by 25% plus what is the fund
value? It is the maximum that is paid last. With that, the
PAN is completed.
This is how customer service works. If
nothing unfortunate happens in the meantime, the
PAN
works. Now imagine that the second condition is that
unfortunate death occurs in
this signature plan.
Suppose a 35-year-old person takes a plan with a premium payment term of seven years and a premium term of 20 years. The
premium is Rs. 2 lakhs. The
sum assured is Rs. 20 lakhs. After
paying the second premium at the age of 37, if the person dies, then
Rs. 20 lakhs will be paid
as sum assured to the nominee. After that,
the company
ICC Prudential will pay all the remaining premiums. Waiver of
premium will be paid.
From the third year, 10% sum assured will be paid up to 20
years. From the third year, Rs. 2 lakhs will be kept
here and will continue to be paid here. The nominee will keep paying Rs. 2 lakhs every year i.e. third year fourth year fifth year and so on till
20 years.
Here the premium is not paid at the
last fund value i.e. how much is the fund value at the end of the total 20-
year term. If you
think that the fund value will be paid at the end of the 20-year term, this is what the fund value will be
This plan is coming now, the
total customer is paying here is ₹4 lakh
rupees. Here, the customer has got this income in
this case, after saying this for
17 years, 2 lakh 34 lakhs have been
received here. The total premium
paid by the company for the remaining seven years is
40 lakh rupees, 40 plus as
mentioned here, 13 20 65
lakhs, the total paid here
is 4 lakhs, 60 65 lakhs have been received
here. The nominee has
a good reason, that is, even
after living, we have a well
creation, that is, we can pay and create a
good amount of corpus. If
death occurs, we can also create a corpus. We will also get
an amount for death.
Now, all this can be
used as tuition fees. This
can be used for child education, child marriage, etc.
I
feel this plan is a complete plan. If you
like the plan video,
anyway.  Press the like button and let's
look at the key benefits of the plan. There is no premium allocation charge. This was
a complaint that everyone had about ULI plans in general.
Now, in general,
very few allocation charges are
charged in all plans. Because of the IR specification, there is a
zero allocation charge.
Systematic withdrawal plan is
available here. That is, once an amount is
reached, we have systematic withdrawal like a pension. There is a
premium waiver benefit. I
said earlier that premium waiver benefit is
available in this plan. Now, let's
look at the entry conditions of the plan. The minimum premium is ₹60,000. The
minimum premium is ₹60,000. Those in the age band of
18 to 50 years can
join this plan. Then, if the premium term is below
45 years, you can choose a term of up to 20 years.
Above 45, you can choose a term of up to 20 years.  If you are
15 years old, you can choose 15 years. Since it is a
universal plan, I am
saying that we
can stop the plan at any time after five years. That is, if
we are not alive or if we are unfortunate,
then we should continue the
policy until the term because there are
many benefits.
Similarly, if the premium payment term is below 45, we
can select five to 15 years. If you are above 45, you
can select seven to 15 years. As
I said earlier, the premium allocation charge is zero. The
policy administration charge is ₹500 per month, the
maximum is up to
6000. The fund management charge
is 135% of the mortality charge. In this, the base
sub-measured plus the mortal charge of the premium plus
income benefit will also be
taken. Your wealth  I hope you
liked the video about ICICI Prudential Signature Ashur, which is one of the best plans for creation and now in case of unfortunate family support in your absence. If you like it, you should like it
anyway. Similarly, if you want to
purchase this plan, you
can whatsapp me on this number. You can whatsapp
me. You can call me. You can also whatsapp me to purchase
any plan of ICICI Prudential. If you have not
subscribed to this channel yet, then
subscribe. Until we
see you in the next video,
bye bye to everyone.